# Ganesh Hegde

# Software Engineer III @ Groww



in ganesh28hegde ## 28/04/1993

## **Education**

B.E in ECE, R. V. College of Engineering 2011 - 2015 | Bengaluru, India CGPA: 8.71. Data structures & Algorithms, Java were the major learnings.

Science, Chaitanya P. U. College 2009 - 2011 | Sirsi, Karnataka, India Scored 95% overall. Secured rank 395 in CET.

#### **Profile**

Passionate engineer with 6+ years of hands-on developing experience in maintainable software.

Learning new technologies over the course of my professional career and have the ability to adapt to technology changes.

Experienced working in a bootstrap startup and a startup which scaled 10x.

## **Interests**

**Chess** ☑ (Global rank: 52,595 @ chess.com), **Entrepreneurship** ☑ (Simplified platform for HRs),

Cricket, Tennis, Football

#### **Skills**

Frontend Development (Javascript, React, Redux, Service Worker),

People Management (Ownership, Leadership, Motivate, Communicative),

**Backend Development** (Ruby, Rails, Meta Programming, ORM, RVM),

Mobile App Development (Java, Flutter, MVP, MVVM, Eye for Design)

# **Professional Experience**

# **Software Engineer III,** *Groww* □

2022 - present | Bengaluru, India

- Actively contribute to decide OKRs, plan and execution.
- Supervising the work of multiple teams. Providing them clear and concise instructions if needed.
- Manage and help people to get the maximum potential. Regular 1:1s to solve concerns and help them to grow.
- Contributing in major architectural changes.

## **Software Engineer II,** *Groww* ☑

2021 - 2022 | Bengaluru, India

- Review PRs, design technical architecture for product requirements.
- Actively participated in hiring interns to senior developers for frontend, backend.
- Contributed in launching F&O feature from scratch.
- Impact: Removed egress traffic resulting in reduction of billing to nearly 5 lakh/month.

## **Software Engineer I,** *Groww* □

2020 - 2021 | Bengaluru, India

- Part of team which shipped onboarding feature from scratch on mobile site.
- Contributed in launching stock delivery/intraday features.
- Contributed in launching IPO.
- Played role of proactively gathering product requirements, design and ship features at rocket velocity.

# Full Stack Developer, Officepulse (Treflo) ☑

2017 - 2020 | Bengaluru, India

- Responsible for all aspects of frontend/backend architecture, development, deployment. (React, Ruby on Rails)
- Rapid development of a procurement platform for offices/large enterprises conceptualisation, working software, customer trials.
- Impact & Scale: Revenue reached peak 4 cr/month, more than 300 companies onboarded.
- Learning: Continuously adapting to everchanging react design patterns, best practices, creating standalone UI components.
- Learning: Managed team of developers, increased the development productivity.

Mobile App Developer, QuickRide ☐ 07/2016 – 2017 | Bengaluru, India Built car pooling application for corporate employees.

# **Mobile App Developer,** *Healthplix* ☑ 2016 – 06/2016 | Bengaluru, India

- Exposure to modern mobile development architectures (MVP, MVVM), clean code practices.
- Built reminder feature for patients. Which reminds them to take pills.

**Precision Engineer,** *Titan Company Limited* 2015 – 2016 | Hosur, India Worked on machine building / automation using PLC

## **Declaration**

I hereby declare that the above particulars of facts and information stated are correct to the best of my belief and knowledge.

**GANESH HEGDE** 

Bengaluru